Finding Aids to Personal Papers and Special Collections in the VMFA Archives Leslie Cheek, Jr. Personal Papers, 1931-1993 SC-02
VMFA Archives
- Series 4: Personal Files, 1934-1992; SC-02-04; 211 folders;; 25 items
  - AIV-list of AIV's relevant to Cheek biography, 1960-1969 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 400)
  - UNESCO-Richmond News Leader clippings of Cheek as member of UNESCO, 1959 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 401)
  - AIV'S-newspaper clipping review of AIV, v.6 #3 Spring 66, v.6 #1 Fall 65, v.7#2 Winter 67, v.3#1 Fall 62, v.9 #1 Fall 68, 1962-1968 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 402)
  - Additions to museum-miscellaneous clippings and correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 403)
  - Cheek's ideas on museums and arts in general-paper on BMA for AAM 1940 and other articles by Cheek on W&M and other museums, in "Magazine Of Art," March 1938, 1938-1940 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 404)
  - VMFA 1966-Cheek's remarks for Trustee meeting, "American Painting '66" catalog, newspaper clipping (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 405)
  - VMFA Hollywood exhibition-"George Stevens Makes A Film," newspaper clippings and proposals, 1955 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 406)
  - 1965-Louden County Chapter program 1965-1966, newspaper clippings, Artmobile Inaugural Parade (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 407)
  - 1964-Blue Ridge Chapter Program 1963-1964, newspaper clippings (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 408)
  - 1963-10th Anniversary of the Artmobile (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 409)
  - Retirement clippings, undated (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 410)
  - Clips, Design in Scandinavia, Scandinavian newspapers, 1953 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 411)
  - Baltimore Sun article, Edith Lindeman, 1968 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 412)
  - Society of Architectural Historians, Architectural Tour, Oct. 1969 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 413)
  - Museum information, 1968-1969 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 414)
  - New York cocktail party, Nov. 1968 (Box SC-02 Box 9, Folder Folder 415)
  - Correspondence-Cheek, C. Humelsine, and Mrs. A. I. Dupont, Colonial Williamsburg and Anheuser-Busch project, exhibitions, checklists, theatre programs, newspaper clippings, 1949-1969 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 416)
  - Schedules-event schedules, trip itineraries, 1961 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 417)
  - Resignation and restoration clippings-Arthur H. Ballet, undated (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 418)
  - Resignation-George Gibson, Morton Thalhimer, Cheek resignation and related correspondence, 1937-1958 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 419)
  - Resignation letters of support, 1958 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 420)
  - Meeting with Mr. Will, September 3, 1968-E. Will, Cheek retirement and related correspondence, Sep. 1968 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 421)
  - Correspondence regarding retirement, 1967-1971 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 422)
  - Virginia Museum correspondence, 1969-81-Peter Mooz and various museum staff, covering social events, Cheek's tenure as Director Emeritus, theatre, 1957-1958 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 423)
  - Luncheon, Saam Nystad, April 21, 1983-Pinkney Near and Saam Nystad, purchase of Steen's "The Letter," and Nystad's visit to museum, Apr. 1983 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 424)
  - Museum years, correspondence-Morton Thalhimer, charts, statistics, statements during Cheek years, museum significant dates, Cheek background, resume, Distinguished Service Award, 1960-1984 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 425)
  - J. Carter Brown, undated (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 426)
  - J. Carter Brown thesis-J, Carter Brown's thesis of Virginia Museum (1960), resume, retirement, news clippings, 1960-1992 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 427)
  - Correspondence-Monroe Bush, Governor Almond, G. Gibson, reception for Almond, 1958 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 428)
  - Correspondence: G. Gibson, Richard Reynolds, museum chart of organization, membership appeal, 1956-1957 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 429)
  - Cheek retirement, 1953-1964 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 430)
  - Correspondence regarding Cheek becoming director, June 1948-July 1960/salary information, June 1948-1960 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 431)
  - Letters to Cheek regarding 1968 retirement and awards I, 1966-1971 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 432)
  - Letters to Cheek regarding 1968 retirement and awards II, 1966-1971 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 433)
  - Museum data, 1949-1968 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 434)
  - McCarthy, Mr. Frank-executive producer of 20th Century Fox, biographical data, Virginia Theatre Arts system, proposal for Art of Filmmaking, Ford Foundation grant for VM theatre, letter to Shirley MacLaine, 1954-1968 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 435)
  - VMFA 1966 Annual Meeting-proposals for Part I: "Present Problems of the Virginia Artist and Craftsmen in Regard to his Education and Support" and Part II "Establishment, Maintenance and Operation of a Project to Provide Experience and Instruction in the Dramatic Arts for Children and Adults," report of the President, newspaper clippings (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 436)
  - VMFA news clips, correspondence, 1967 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 437)
  - Virginia State Library, Correspondence-Paul Perrot, letters of permission to access Virginia State Library and Archives file regarding museum by Richmond Temple for Cheek biography, receipt forms, 1983-1984 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 438)
  - Members' Suite-photocopied images of members' suite, article on its design and related correspondence, 1955-1983 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 439)
  - Christmas at the museum-short essay by Cheek and related correspondence, 1983 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 440)
  - Cinevision/Muscarelle Museum-correspondence with Glen Lowry (W&M) about Smithsonian project grant from Time, Inc., "Hollywood: Legend and Reality," Muscarelle Museum Annual Report, 1983-1984 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 441)
  - "Movable Walls and Lighting in the Virginia Museum in Richmond, Virginia"-includes photocopies of installations and article by Carroll B. Lusk on museum lighting, photos, 1965 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 442)
  - Correspondence with Armand Hammer regarding Pratt Faberge collection, 1986-1989 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 443)
  - VMFA printed material, 1965-1968 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 444)
  - North Wing addition-photographs, negatives, architectural renderings, drawings, models, 1964 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 445)
  - Newspaper supplement on VMFA, 1961 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 446)
  - Newspaper clippings on VMFA history, 1965-1984 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 447)
  - Correspondence-Mellon exhibition, "Painting in England, 1700-1850", June 1960-May 1963 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 448)
  - Correspondence-exhibit plans and preparation, "Painting in England, 1700-1850", June 1960-Oct. 1963 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 449)
  - Checklist, "Painting in England, 1700-1850", 1963 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 450)
  - Cheek fan mail-fan mail for "Treasures In America, 25th Anniversary of VM", 1961-1979 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 451)
  - Cheek's writings-various articles on architecture and design, 1940 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 452)
  - Clippings, 1957 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 453)
  - Clippings, 1958 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 454)
  - Paul Perrot-correspondence between Perrot and Cheek, Perrot retirement announcement, 1990-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 455)
  - Faberge Jewels-Harry Brooks, Victor Hammer, inquiries concerning the acquisition of Faberge Jewels, 1983-1987 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 456)
  - "The Virginia Arts", undated (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 457)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 458)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 459)
  - Virginia Museum 1987-correspondence (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 460)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 461)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 462)
  - Correspondence-Fred Brandt, Cheek monetary contribution, 1991-1992 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 463)
  - Lee, Katherine-general information and museum events, 1991-1992 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 464)
  - David Curry-"At Home: American Art in the Virginia Museum" exhibition, correspondence regarding museum collections, 1991 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 465)
  - Museum background-articles on Cheek's background and personal history, undated (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 466)
  - Shu Knoll interiors, VMFA 1954-photo, article on Knoll (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 467)
  - Theatre dedication ceremony, Jan. 18, 1990 (Box SC-02 Box 10, Folder Folder 468)
  - U.S. Information Agency handbook, Jan. 1961, activities report, incomplete (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 469)
  - People to people-inception/founding, 1957 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 470)
  - People to people-summary of activities and highlights, 1957-1961 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 471)
  - People to people-organizational proposal, newsletters, other related printed material, 1957-1961 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 472)
  - People to people-program and events, David Finley (chair of Fine Arts Committee) and Cheek, 1956-1957 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 473)
  - People to people, 1958 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 474)
  - People to people, 1960 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 475)
  - People to people, Jan.-June 1961 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 476)
  - People to people, July-Dec. 1961 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 477)
  - People to people, Jan.-Feb. 1962 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 478)
  - People to people, Mar.-May 1962 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 479)
  - People to people, June-July 1962 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 480)
  - Essay, VMFA theatre, undated (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 481)
  - Theatre Virginia 1989-articles on Bob Telford (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 482)
  - Theatre-printed material, Xeroxed photographs, 1950s-1980s (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 483)
  - VM Theatre history, undated (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 484)
  - Concerts at the Virginia Museum Theatre-The Richmond Chamber Music Society, also correspondence regarding Herod Cannon Memorial Chapel, "The Eager Listener", 1959-1960 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 485)
  - VM Theatre clips, undated (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 486)
  - VMFA Council-formation 1955-1960s, early activities, newspaper clippings, history, 1955-1980 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 487)
  - VMFA Fellows-formation and updates, correspondence with Paul Mellon and members, statement of purposes, history, 1955-1984 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 488)
  - Fellows correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 489)
  - Early Artmobile-correspondence with Neil November about Sara November as the creator of Art-on-Wheels project via Valentine museum around 1934, newspaper clippings, 1934-Nov. 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 490)
  - Exhibitions-"Healy's Sitters", 1950 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 491)
  - Photocopied photos of lecturers and jurors, exhibition installations, etc., 1950-1968 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 492)
  - Exhibitions-"Skidmore, Owings, and Merrill," architectural, Reynolds Metals magazine, 1958 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 493)
  - Exhibitions-"Home Front 1861," "Sport and the Horse" 1960, a 1987 outline for "Home Front 1861", 1960-1987 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 494)
  - "Photography in the Fine Arts," Exhibition V, 1967, Cheek on board of selection (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 495)
  - Photographs of exhibitions, mainly "Home Front 1861," also "Tastemakers" and "Romanticism", 1961 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 496)
  - Photographs-VMFA events, theatre, Artmobile, exhibits, 1954-1963 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 497)
  - South Wing Addition-test boring survey, undated (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 498)
  - PAVE: "School for Wives", undated (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 499)
  - National Foundation for the Arts and Humanities Act of 1965 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 500)
  - Medieval Hall acoustics, undated (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 501)
  - Museum library, including 1957 proposal (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 502)
  - Interstate Interagency Committee on Recreation, undated (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 503)
  - IRS rulings, 1958 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 504)
  - Britain's National Art Collections Fund, 1964 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 505)
  - Homer and the Sea, 1964 (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 506)
  - Keys, undated (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 507)
  - Kitchen Equipment, undated (Box SC-02 Box 11, Folder Folder 508)
  - Fellowships, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 509)
  - Fellows-retired, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 510)
  - Fellows-speeches, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 511)
  - Exhibitions-Thalhimer (Sandwich Glass), undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 512)
  - Exhibition schedule-loans beginning with 1959/1960 season (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 513)
  - Furniture exhibition, 1640-1820, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 514)
  - Publicity regarding Southern furniture exhibition, 1640-1820, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 515)
  - Furniture of the South, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 516)
  - Miscellaneous clips-newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 517)
  - VMFA clippings-newspaper clippings, Cheek membership of UNESCO, chair of American Federation of the Arts, retirement, Mellon clippings, programs and events, Ross Valentine's columns on art, 1959-1983 (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 518)
  - 25th anniversary clips-newspaper clippings, Junior League article, 1961 (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 519)
  - Clippings, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 520)
  - Social planning and programs for Reston, Virginia, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 521)
  - Mr. Cheek-Reston, Virginia, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 522)
  - Stankobitz project, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 523)
  - Retirement, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 524)
  - Retirement dinner, May 1969 (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 525)
  - Retirement-letters, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 526)
  - Retirement, Oct. 1968 (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 527)
  - Cheek - miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 528)
  - William and Mary, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 529)
  - Newspaper article and editorial, Leslie Cheek Jr., Dec. 1992 (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 530)
  - Cavalcade, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 531)
  - Post-retirement projects, undated (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 532)
  - 18 January luncheon, 1990 (Box SC-02 Box 12, Folder Folder 533)
  - Charter day, W&M, 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 534)
  - "Sentimental Journey", Sep. 14, 1981 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 535)
  - Clippings, undated (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 536)
  - Farewell party for Bob Telford, June 9, 1966 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 537)
  - Newspaper articles, Leslie Cheek, Jr., 1992 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 538)
  - Harvard 25th reunion, June 10-14, 1956 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 539)
  - Museum entertaining, undated (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 540)
  - Clippings and printed material, undated (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 541)
  - J. Carter Brown thesis, 1960 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 542)
  - Binder, "Virginia Museum, 1948-1968" I (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 543)
  - Binder, "Virginia Museum, 1948-1968" II (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 544)
  - RESTRICTED: Correspondence regarding retirement/VSRS, 1967-1971 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 545)
  - RESTRICTED: Accessions Committee mailings-James Asa Shield, acquisition of Egyptian antiquities from the Metropolitan, objects in museum collection in need of repair, 1957-1958 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 546)
  - RESTRICTED: Notes on conversation with Vincent Bowditch (museum theatre) and his resignation, 1956 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 547)
  - RESTRICTED: Long-term loans, 1969 (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 548)
  - RESTRICTED: Legal matters, including bequests, deaccessions, undated (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 549)
  - RESTRICTED: Investments and securities, undated (Box SC-02 Box 16, Folder Folder 550)
  - "The School for Wives, Exterior," set design by Jack Doepp, 1985 (Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 2)
  - "The School for Wives, Interior," set design by Jack Doepp, 1985 (Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 2)
  - "The Virginia Room for the New York World's Fair '39," drawing by Leslie Cheek, [1939] (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "Perspective View of Stair Hall," drawing by Leslie Cheek from "Above it All: The Top Ten Floors of an 85-Story Skyscraper" Graduation Thesis at Yale, 1935 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "Section Through Stage, Restaurant, Hall, Lounge," drawing by Leslie Cheek from "Above it All: The Top Ten Floors of an 85-Story Skyscraper" Graduation Thesis at Yale, 1935 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "Roof Level, Plan at Level 'A,' Plan at Level 'B,'" drawing by Leslie Cheek from "Above it All: The Top Ten Floors of an 85-Story Skyscraper" Graduation Thesis at Yale, 1935 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "Plan at Level 'C,' Plan at Level 'E,' Plan at Level 'F,'" drawing by Leslie Cheek from "Above it All: The Top Ten Floors of an 85-Story Skyscraper" Graduation Thesis at Yale, 1935 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "Plan at Level 'G,' Plan at Level 'H,' Typical Floor 2nd Elevator Bank," drawing by Leslie Cheek from "Above it All: The Top Ten Floors of an 85-Story Skyscraper" Graduation Thesis at Yale, 1935 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "At Home: American Art at the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1700-1950", 1991 (Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 3)
  - Exterior drawing of proposed VMFA North wing entrance, [1965?] (Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 1)
  - 13 bound Artmobile drawings by Hankins and Johann, July-Dec. 1961 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 2)
  - "The Department of Fine Arts," drawing by Leslie Cheek, [Early 1940s] (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Clippings, prayers, and program for Leslie Cheek's memorial service, Dec. 1992 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 2)
  - "Mr. Leslie Cheek Jr. has been elected a member of the Phi Beta Kappa Fraternity, Alpha Chapter...Harvard University", June 1931 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "Legend: Cheek's indelible stamp wasn't all by 'accident,'" RTD clipping, Sep. 1981 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "Rear Wall Elevation for 'The Marquise,' UPG, West Falmouth," set design by Leslie Cheek, 1930 (Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 1)
  - Photograph of Leslie Cheek, Pamela Brown, and John Carter Brown at the Muscarelle Museum of Art, Oct. 1984 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "Sir Ivor - The Derby Stakes 1968" mounted photograph with inscription about Raymond Guest (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Untitled office interior, drawing by Leslie Cheek, undated (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "Suggested Sign for the Junior League's New Senior Center at 909 West Franklin Street," drawing by Leslie Cheek with copy, Nov. 1958 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - "Romanticism in America," drawing by Leslie Cheek, [1940] (Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 1)
  - "Main Floor Plan, 'Romanticism in America,'" drawing by Leslie Cheek, 1940 (Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 1)
  - "Arts in Virginia," Leslie Cheek's personal copy, 1960-1968 (Oversize SC-02 Realia 1)
  - Photograph of Leslie and Mary Tyler at 4703 Pocahontas, undated (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 2)
  - Photograph of Leslie in front of museum construction, undated (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 2)
- Series 5: Awards and Degrees, 1931-1993; SC-02-05; 8 folders;; 20 items
  This series is comprised of correspondence about and the actual awards and degrees conferred upon Cheek throughout his life.
  - Chamber of Commerce Award, May 8, 1969-award of distinguished service, May 1969 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 551)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award speech, September 16, 1966-letters of compliment and replies, remarks of the Public Relations Society of America, newspaper clippings, Sep. 1966 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 552)
  - Awards, 1987-1988 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 553)
  - Bravo awards, 1979 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 554)
  - AIA award, Oct. 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 555)
  - Cheek-awards, undated (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 556)
  - Cheek-degrees, undated (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 557)
  - Governor's Awards for the Arts, 1979 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 558)
  - The First Governor's Awards for the Arts, 1969 (Oversize SC-02 Realia 1)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce Special Award, May 1969 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Thomas Jefferson Citation for Public Service, Sep. 1966 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - The Federated Arts Council of Richmond Annual Award, Mar. 1981 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - The Governor's Awards for the Arts, Nov. 1979 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Doctor of Fine Arts Degree, Washington and Lee University, June 1983 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Doctor of Fine Arts Degree, William and Mary College, Feb. 1967 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - State resolution granting honorary degree of Patron of the Arts, 1977 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Senate Joint Resolution No. 202, Jan. 1993 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Bachelor of Arts Degree, Yale University, June 1935 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Doctor of Fine Arts Degree, University of Richmond, Oct. 1955 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Bachelor of Science Degree, Harvard University, June 1931 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Architecture Degree, Yale University, June 1935 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Senate Joint Resolution No. 221, Feb. 1989 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Virginia Society American Institute of Architects Architectural Medal for Virginia Service, Sep. 1985 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - Doctor of Humane Letters Degree, Virginia Union University, May 1988 (Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1)
  - The Virginia Chapter of the American Society of Interior Designers George Washington Award, 1981 (Oversize SC-02 Realia 1)
  - "To Leslie Cheek Jr. from Board of Trustees of Newport News Public Library in Appreciation", May 1957 (Oversize SC-02 Realia 1)
  - Virginia Museum Patron of the Arts Medal, 1977 (Oversize SC-02 Realia 1)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts Webster S. Rhoads Medal, undated (Oversize SC-02 Realia 1)
- Series 6: Travel, 1952-1980; SC-02-06; 37 folders
  This series is comprised of correspondence, itineraries, and programs detailing the Cheeks' personal travels around the world.
  - List of Trips, 1953-1980 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 559)
  - Mayflower Cruise, 1970 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 560)
  - South Seas Kungsholm Cruise, 1969 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 561)
  - Hydrofoil trip-James River to Brandon, June 1965 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 562)
  - Italian journey, February-March, 1956, Feb.-Mar. 1956 (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 563)
  - Egypt, undated (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 564)
  - Brussels trip, undated (Box SC-02 Box 13, Folder Folder 565)
  - Mediterranean Cruise Gripsholm, March 6-April 26, 1972, Mar.-Apr. 1972 (Box SC-02 Box 14, Folder Folder 566)
  - Swedish American Line packet, world trip, January-April, 1973, Jan.-Apr. 1973 (Box SC-02 Box 14, Folder Folder 567)
  - London, Switzerland, etc., December 17, 1977-January 7, 1978, Dec. 1977-Jan. 1978 (Box SC-02 Box 14, Folder Folder 568)
  - Greek islands, Mediterranean, Adriatic, 1975 (Box SC-02 Box 14, Folder Folder 569)
  - Hudson River trip, July 22-30, 1977, July 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 14, Folder Folder 570)